Sanchit Sharma

Personal Profile:

I am an intelligent, enthusiastic, responsible and hard-working junior Developer and DevOps Engineer. I have significant experience working both working within and helping to organise small scrum teams (5 members and fewer) and am a Certified Scrum Master. I have excellent communication skills and can present well – I am capable of showing the detail in my work, but also the bigger picture where necessary.

Address	507a Hackney Road, London, E2 9ED
Email	sanchitsharma1@gmail.com
Phone	07565778022
Github	https://github.com/Sandvich

Education:

Knowledge Academy	Certified Scrum Master	
Imperial College, London	BSc Geophysics, 2:2, completed 2015. Primarily 1 st in physics, maths and computing modules. (References available if required.)	
Knights Templar School, Baldock	A2 Maths: A* Physics: A Further Maths: A	AS Maths: A Physics: A Further Maths: A French: A

Work Experience and Past Employment:

I and the second	
February 2016-May 2017: Vocal Planet Ltd - Junior Developer	I worked as part of a small scrum team in Vocal Planet, primarily focusing on the infrastructure and database requirements of the team. The key things I learned were the software development lifecycle, test driven development and continuous integration. I helped to develop a master data management solution which has yet to enter the market, and made extensive use of JDBC, SQLAlchemy, Django and Flask.
Summer 2013: Imperial College London Summer placement in the Applied Modelling & Computation Group	During this placement I learned about fluid dynamics and computational modelling. I worked alongside computational physicists in the department and delivered a tool to convert templates from the Ecolab software package to their open source Fluidity program. The project was done within a Ubuntu Linux environment, and written in Python with the Pyparsing module.
2011 : Xerox Ltd Assistant Scrum Master – 10 weeks	I worked alongside some of their scrum teams, helping to manage the teams and also to develop tools to measure their metrics and performance. This was primarily done in Python and HTML5.
November 2009-April 2011: Maplin Part time sales advisor	I expanded my knowledge of electronics and computing and proved my problem solving skills. I developed good people skills while working at Maplin.

2009 : Xerox Ltd summer placement – five weeks	I worked on a commercially sensitive printer technology which has not yet entered the market. I learned research skills, communication skills and some programming. Despite coming across new mathematical concepts as part of this, I completed the project to a high standard. As a result, a patent application was submitted for my work.
2008 : EADS Astrium (work placement – one week)	I worked in the satellite department to analyse a specific project path for the department to pursue. I had to collect large amounts of information about current projects similar to the one they were considering. In order to understand all the information that was available, I discussed the problem with my colleagues and learned from them to improve my own understanding. I effectively researched and presented this to my manager.

Computing System Experience

- I use Scrum in my own projects on various scales, and am a certified Scrum Master.
- I built my own PC at the age of 13.
- I am fluent in bash/ansible and have experience setting up and running servers.
- I use Linux extensively and am extremely confident with it.
- I am fluent in Python, Java and C++
- I am confident with C, Javascript, HTML and Matlab.
- I have used C#, UML, PICAXE BASIC and Wolfram Mathematica.
- Writing code clearly and documenting it properly are things I do automatically.
- I understand and embrace Scrum and Agile programming methods.
- I have experience developing APIs.
- I have experience using various public APIs including SteamSpy and TfL, working with both JSON and XML.
- I primarily work on backends, but am able to integrate into frontends and have build a few of my own using QT/C++, JavaFX/Java, PyGame/Python and Tkinter/Python.
- I have skill in data processing, including the use of filters to improve the signal to noise ratio in real-life data and large scale simulation.
- I have analysed large volumes of data sorting and bucketing data appropriately, using tools to remove outliers.

Achievements

- 2016: Myself and a friend took part in a game jam and together we wrote a game limited to 64x64 pixels using python and pygame which is available online today.
- 2014: I began to write my own tabletop RPG, which was picked up by a publisher in December of that year it was published in 2016.
- 2012-2015 I helped to maintain several societies at Imperial College on a voluntary basis, and for two of these years this was a crucial role without which said societies would not have functioned.
- 2011-2015 I created and ran two gaming groups.
- 2009 I wrote a proof-of-concept for which a patent application was submitted (see Xerox).
- 2009 I took part in and won Young Enterprise day working together with my form in Knights Templar.
- 2007 I represented my school in the Maths Challenge run at the University of Cambridge

Interests

My interests include: Physics especially in Quantum mechanics and Astrophysics, Computing, Anime/Manga, Gaming, Text/Tabletop RPGs, Fencing, Reading, Electronics, Puzzles and Riddles.